[narrator] Heavens Arena.
The 251-story building
which stands 991-meter tall,
is a mecca for fighters.
When combatants win a fight,
they may advance by one class,
and receive a corresponding reward.
After reaching the 100th floor,
they are assigned a private room.
And those contestants
who are skilled and fortunate enough
to reach the 200th floor
earn the right to challenge
the strongest fighters, the Floor Masters,
in an intense battle for survival.
This is without a doubt
the best stage a warrior could ask for.
[theme song playing]
You say that your brother...
is able to use Nen?
I need to understand
what Nen and Ren even mean!
And not just halfway.
I need to know it!
Well, in that case…
NEN X AND X NEN
[narrator] After Killua fought Zushi,
the young practitioner
of Shingen-ryu martial arts,
Zushi mentioned the Four Exercises.
Gon and Killua are about to learn
the secret of those principles
from Zushi’s master, Wing.
[Wing] Paying attention?
Nen, or flame,
is a power that fires our souls.
In other words,
it’s the strength of your will.
NEN (FLAME)
And the Four Exercises
is a training regimen
that strengthens your will.
“Strengthens your will”
Training?
-[pen squeaking on the board]
-[Wing] Correct.
TEN (POINT)
[wing]
Ten: focus the mind on a single point,
reflect on the self,
and determine the goal.
ZETSU (TONGUE)
Zetsu: to put into words.
REN (TEMPER)
Ren is to intensify your will.
HATSU (RELEASE)
Hatsu is to release it into action.
[Gon] Ten. Zetsu. Ren. Hatsu.
The Four Exercises.
See, Zushi tempered his ‘refusal to lose’
during his battle with you, Killua.
[shuddering breath]
[Wing] Now allow me to demonstrate.
Killua?
For this demonstration,
I would like to “kill” you now.
Is that all right?
Sure. Why not.
But you won’t be able to.
Let’s do this in order.
First, Ten.
I focus my mind on a single point.
Zetsu:
Express your desired intent.
Either mentally or verbally.
I will kill you.
[quiet grunt]
That was a taste of Ren.
With enough strength and focus,
the will functions as action or Hatsu.
With a strong will
your opponent will back down.
A more familiar term would be ‘bluffing’.
Ren hardens that which is soft
and you suddenly find
that you’ve lost your ability
to correct an incorrect idea.
Therefore, until your soul
has fully matured,
avoid using Ren.
As it stands now,
you three boys should really focus
on training your souls.
[Killua] Let's go, Gon.
[Wing]
If you truly wish to learn about Nen,
set your sights on mastering Ten first.
If you master Ten,
you no longer feel the pressure
of an opponent’s will.
[Gon] Thank you very much!
Wait up, Killua!
-[Wing] Zushi.
-Yes, sir?
[Wing] Let's begin training.
Oh... Osu!
First off…
[Gon] He lied?
Yeah.
What he said was true, far as it went
and his power is the real deal, too.
There are a few things it doesn’t cover.
Like?
[Killua] Like how tough Zushi is.
In our fight,
he got up every time I knocked him down.
That was pretty annoying.
Which is why I got
a little pushy with him at the end.
[cheering]
[panting]
Why, you--!
[gasps]
Oops!
[commentator]
Oooh! Zushi sails out of the ring!
And straight to the hospital,
by the looks of it!
That’s gotta hurt!
[cheering]
[commentator] He’s gotten back up, folks!
Zushi must be invincible!
[panting]
[Killua] No way…
[commentator] But the referee has awarded
a critical hit and knockdown.
Killua wins by TKO, with 11 total points.
[cheering]
It wasn’t his strength of will alone
that kept him standing that whole time.
There’s gotta be something else
he’s hiding.
[Wing] What’s the matter, Zushi?
Your Ten is aggravated.
Master...
[Wing] Hm?
Why did you lie to Gon and Killua
just now?
Lie?
Are you referring to my explanation?
[Zushi] Yes!
The Four Exercises are Ten, Zetsu,
Ren and Hatsu.
But they don’t mean what you told them.
Did you decide to lie to them
because they aren’t your students?
FLAME
[Wing] I didn't lie.
That ‘Nen’ is an important discipline
in training the mind...
[pen squeaking on the board]
...for this Nen.
NEN (MIND FORCE)
However, it’s true that I cannot teach Nen
to someone who is not a student.
So, I used the other Nen as a hint,
just to help them along.
If the Nen I teach
is used in the wrong way,
it can become a terrible weapon, Zushi.
For example…
[paper tearing]
You could turn a simple piece of paper
into quite a harmful blade.
Furthermore, you could harden your body
as a defensive measure.
With enough work, anyone can use Nen.
Which is why
you must be very careful
when choosing who to teach it to.
Master…
It’s just...
that I hadn’t gotten the chance
to read that book yet.
Huh?
And that juice…
it was mine…
[Wing mumbles]
[Wing] I’m sorry!
[cheering]
[commentator] It’s time
for the biggest match of the day!
Two rookies have advanced
to the 190th floor
without losing a single fight!
Gon and Killua!
Will they be able to clear
today’s match in one shot, too?
Okay, everyone!
Get ready to press your wager buttons!
[Kung Fu guy] [scoffs]
Unfortunately for you,
that little push move of yours
won’t work on me.
That’s because...
I’m as slippery as a snake,
and my fangs are just as sharp.
Fangs that are just dying
for a taste of your vital points.
[Wrestler] [laughs]
You might sport a vicious chop, kid,
but it won’t be enough
to save you from these muscles!
And do you wanna know why?
[grunts]
Because I’m totally ripped, obviously!
[sighs]
And begin!
[kung fu kiai]
[roaring]
[cheering]
That’s a critical hit and knockdown!
That’s three points! It’s a knock out!
And, winner is Gon!
Critical hit and knockdown!
That’s three points!
Knockout!
Killua wins!
[cheering]
[commentator] Once again, Gon and Killua
have knocked out their opponents
with one attack,
meaning both of them have successfully
cleared the 190th floor!
Both competitors advance
to the 200th floor!
The 200th floor already?!
[Wing] Zushi.
Master, Wing!
Killua and Gon have already reached
the 200th, have they?
Yes! They’re both amazing fighters!
I really need to train m--
What the--?
Master?
[Wing]
I guess I don’t have a choice.
Enjoy.
The 200th floor!
So, what’s it like?
Beats me.
Never actually been there.
But I guess we’re gonna find out.
[elevator dings]
[Gon] Wow!
The 200th floor sure is fancy, huh?
[Killua] Where’s reception?
RECEPTION DESK
[Killua] Maybe this way?
We finally made it!
Yeah.
[both gasp]
[Gon] What is this?
It suddenly feels like we’re in a jungle
swarming with monsters!
But it looks like an ordinary hallway.
Let’s go.
We can do this!
RECEPTION DESK
[Gon] It’s not working…
I can’t go on!
I don’t want to!
Do you feel that bloodlust?
It’s directed right at us!
[straining exhale]
[Killua] Okay, that’s enough!
Who’s there?!
Show yourself!
You must be Killua and Gon.
The reception desk is this way,
so please register
for a 200th match today.
Be advised that your eligibility
for this floor expires at midnight,
so please don’t delay.
Did that feeling come from her?
I can't tell.
By the way, on the 200th floor,
there are currently 173 contestants.
And from this floor up,
all weapons are allowed in all matches.
So, please feel free to use
whatever you have.
Also, as of the 200th floor,
you will no longer receive prize money.
Now you will be fighting only for honor.
Please keep that in mind,
if you participate.
[gasps]
Hi-- Hisoka…
But what are you doing here?
It isn’t that strange, is it?
I love to fight
and this is a temple devoted to the craft.
The real question is why are you here?
Just kidding…
This meeting is no mere coincidence.
I've been waiting for you.
Remember how you ordered your tickets
for the airship over the internet?
With only a little effort on my part,
I was able to find out exactly
when you would arrive.
Well, in any case,
I knew you would come here eventually.
And so...
as your senior,
I have a little bit of a warning
for the both of you.
You’re still not ready
to set foot on this floor.
Not by a long shot.
[Gon and Killua grunting]
[Hisoka]
When you will be depends on your efforts.
For now, leave this floor.
It’s far too early.
[Killua] Wait, what?!
That’s stupid! We just got up here!
I won't let you pass.
But it’s not like you could anyway.
[Killua] [grunts] What the hell…?!
[Gon] What is this?!
[both straining]
[Wing] Don't be reckless!
[Gon] Mr. Wing!
What he’s saying is true.
You have no defense against his Nen.
Nen?
As it stands,
you're both naked in a blizzard,
both of you wondering why it’s so cold.
If you continue to strain your bodies,
you may die.
So, this is Nen?
He can stop us from moving forward
through willpower?
You liar!
Yes. I was lying.
Though some of what I said
was technically true.
I will teach you the truth about Nen.
So, for the time being,
I suggest we withdraw.
Uh ‘scuse me…
[receptionist] Oh yes?
If we don’t register for a fight today,
how would that affect us?
Well, you would have
to start all over again
from the first floor.
Killua, however…
he’s been here before,
and refused to register.
So, if he fails to do so again,
his commitment
will be called into question
and he will be banned from participating.
[Killua] Mr. Wing.
If we withdraw,
will we be able to make it back here
by midnight?
Hmm...
[Wing] That all depends on you.
[Wing] Simply put this is Nen.
Nen refers to the ability
to control your “aura”
which, as you may know,
is also known as life energy.
NEN (MIND FORCE)
Everyone in the world
has a small amount of life energy.
But in most cases,
it simply leaks away.
The ability to build up and contain
this life energy is known as Ten.
is called Ten.
(ENVELOPE)
Using Ten you can make your body tougher
and considerably slow
the effects of aging.
TEN (ENVELOPE)
Then comes Zetsu
which shuts off the flow of aura.
ZETSU (SUPPRESS)
It’s quite effective for concealing
your presence from others
and recovering from fatigue.
Which brings us to Ren,
REN (REFINE)
It enables you to produce more aura.
Can you feel that?
Yeah. It’s like pressure…
But it doesn’t feel weird or creepy.
That’s because I have absolutely
no malice.
I must admit I’m impressed.
Their senses are amazing.
Perhaps it’s a product of the environments
in which they were raised.
But their innate gifts are also a factor.
Aura is an energy dwelling
within all humans…
which makes it very effective
against other humans.
For better or for worse.
If you attack a helpless person
with malice,
you can kill using aura alone.
Only one thing can protect you
from a user of Nen.
You must learn to use it yourself
and use Ten for defense.
Block the other person’s aura
with your own.
Otherwise...
Your body will be shattered
beyond all recognition.
[narrator] Hisoka blocks the path
leading beyond the 200th floor.
Will Gon and Killua
have begun their studies
but will they be able to learn enough
about true Nen to pass Hisoka
and reach the receptionist
all before the clock strikes midnight?
Not yet.
It’s too soon.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] ...Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we're introducing Mr. Wing,
Zushi’s master
and an expert at Shingen-ryu!
It seems like he’s pretty good with Nen.
Oh yeah, but isn’t his shirt untucked?
And he’s got bedhead!
Next time: Awakening x And x Potential!
[Gon grunting]
Did you feel anything?
[Killua] Nope. Nothing.